- **<C>** +91-9952008125
- <E> spraga1995@gmail.com

F1,44/9, Arunachala Apartments, South Street,

 $4^{th}\,Stage\,Lakshmi\,Nagar,\,Nanganallur,$

Chennai- 600061



CAREER OBJECTIVE

A Data science enthusiast with 3 years of professional experience and strong portfolio enhanced through trainings and certifications. Desires to join an innovative, goal-oriented team that provides an opportunity to gain knowledge and practice data science skills. Seeking to begin career with an entry-level position in Data Science and Machine learning role in a fast-paced work environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DEV BIG DATA SE II (SOFTWARE ENGINEER II)

Sysvine Technologies Pvt Ltd, Sept 2021 - Present

- Development of automation scripts using Scala, Python and shell to extract Bigdata from Hive/SQL databases, transform it using Spark and inject to databases.
- Troubleshoot/ Debug errors in Bigdata Automation scripts.
- Maintaining ETL Pipeline/Process.
- Work on different Clusters/Servers and run the automation scripts for processing bigdata.

JUNIOR DATA ENGINEER

Wobot Intelligence Pvt Ltd, Remote/Feb2021- Sept 2021

- Pre-processing data for Computer Vision algorithms using python.
- Infer pre-trained models for dataset generation.
- Building and managing a pipeline for pre-processing data.
- Dataset Curation and Augmentation Techniques.
- Worked with various data formats and performed text extraction in it using python.
- Building Docker Images and Running Docker Containers for inference and testing models.
- Improving quality of data using python.
- Automating the dataset curation process.
- Data Management using AWS S3.
- Scripts for data processing in Python.

DIGITAL ASSOCIATE

Amazon Development Centre, Chennai / Mar 2019 - Feb 2020 (Contract)

- · Handling and Processing data for a Machine learning algorithm
- · Error detection and correction in data.
- · Data Management in Cloud.
- · Using custom tools for pre-processing.
- · Reporting.

TRAINEE

Multivista Global Pvt. Ltd., Chennai /Jan 2018 - Aug 2018

- Trainee support
- Inside Sale

EDUCATION SKILLS

Master of Science in Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence

upGrad Educations in affiliation with IIIT, Bangalore and Liverpool John Moores University, England - completing in 2023

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics

Rajalakshmi Engineering College, Anna University, Chennai, CGPA:7.0, 2017

12th Standard, Computer Science

New Prince Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Chennai, Score:79%, 2013

10th Standard

Prince Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Chennai, Score:83%, 2011

CERTIFICATIONS

- Business Analytics, IMS Proschool, Chennai
- ANIIT for Engineers (Programming), NIIT, Chennai
- Keizan Robotics Program- Level 1, Lema Labs, IIT Madras Research Park, Chennai
- Industrial Automation, Technocrat Automation

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

- Winner of Keizan Robotics Competition Level 1 conducted at IIT Madras Research Park by Lema Labs, Chennai
- Member of organizing committee in "COULOMB 2K15"- symposium by department of Electrical and Electronics, Rajalakshmi Engineering College, Chennai
- Paper Presentation at International conference ICTPACT by IEEE

PROJECTS (https://github.com/spragad)

Sentiment Analysis/Feedback Analysis: A real-time feedback analysis of twitter data using python. Web scraping data from twitter using API, Data cleaning and pre-processing using NLTK and Text-Blob, sentiment scores, analysis of scores and visualization of results.

Regression: A complete solution with python and flask for predicting the number of bikes rented from a bike renting service at Korea. After the analysis, Random Forest Regressor is used for training the model. With Flask and HTML/CSS, a web based interactive app is built using this model and the Demo is hosted on http://spragad.pythonanywhere.com

Detection: A real time detection algorithm in AI using open-source models like Yolo and fine tuning it, to detect humans & their faces. This project has a future scope of face-recognition, activity tracking and many other applications.

Classification: A basic image classification technique done using Convolution Neural Network, using Keras with TensorFlow backend in Python. Trained a Convolution Neural Network model that performs a binary image classification.

I hereby declare that the above particulars furnished by me are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Data Science

- Pvthon
- Shell
- Spark
- Hive
- SQL
- Scala
- AWS S3
- Docker

(PRAGADEESH S)